

# ALEXANDER DOVNAR

LEAD DEVOPS |
CLOUD AND SOLUTIONS ARCHITECT

#### ABOUT ME

DevOps enthusiast with a businessoriented mindset and a track record of successfully overcoming challenges. Experienced in delivering completed projects and available for recommendations upon request.

Active participant in DevOps communities such as DevOps Minsk and DevOps Kitchen Talks, fostering collaboration and staying updated on industry trends.

Outside of work, I prioritize my role as a dedicated family person, cherishing quality time with my wife and two sons. I also indulge in various forms of entertainment during my free time.

### CONTACTS

- Belarus, Minsk
- dovnar.alexander@gmail.com
- +375 (44) 763-25-73
- in /aliaksandrdounar
- https://alex-dovnar.in

#### KEY SKILLS

- Core Skills: AWS, Terraform, Kubernetes
- CI/CD: Jenkins, GitLab CI, GitHub Actions
- Monitoring & Logging: Prometheus, VictoriaMetrics,
   OpenSearch, Loki
- Linux, Networking, Ansible, Python, Bash and more-more.

#### EXPERIENCE

#### Naviteq (naviteq.io) - Lead DevOps Engineer

**JANUARY 2022 - PRESENT** 

- Delivered top-tier DevOps services globally, ensuring high quality and innovation.
- Conducted AWS architecture reviews and optimizations, including FinOps strategies.
- Established DevOps services from inception to "Ideal" status, enhancing efficiency and effectiveness.
- Led internal certification programs, overseeing development, procedures, and learning initiatives.
- Spearheaded the creation of internal products under NDA, contributing to proprietary advancements and solutions.

AWS Terraform Terragrunt Kubernetes (EKS) Helm Bash Python Linux GitHub GHA Oracle Docker CI\CD

## OneSoil (onesoil.ai) - Senior DevOps engineer

AUGUST 2021 - MAY 2022

- Designed and implemented AWS Multi-account strategies, ensuring efficient management and security.
- Spearheaded the adoption of AWS best practices, enhancing reliability and scalability.
- Optimized costs for AWS infrastructure, achieving significant savings while maintaining performance.
- Designed and implemented Kubernetes-based platforms, facilitating scalability and agility in application deployment.

AWS Terraform Terragrunt Kubernetes (EKS) Helm Bash Python Linux Windows GitLab CI Prometheus Grafana

#### EDUCATION

systems

Bachelor's degree: BSUIR
(Belarusian State University of
Informatics and
Radioelectronics) Informational technologies and
management in technical

College: Belarus State Academy of Communication -Technician-programmer in the Networking

#### CERTIFICATES

- AWS Certified Solutions
   Architect Professional (<u>Link</u>)
- AWS Certified Security –
   Specialty (<u>Link</u>)
- HashiCorp Certified: Terraform
   Associate (Link)
- Google Cloud Platform
   Professional Cloud Architect
   (Link)- Expired
- Cisco CCNA

#### CONTACTS

- Belarus, Minsk
- dovnar.alexander@gmail.com
- +375 (44) 763-25-73
- in /aliaksandrdounar
- https://alex-dovnar.in

#### EXPERIENCE

#### DevOps trainer (Slurm and TeachMeSkills)

**AUGUST 2021 - PRESENT** 

- Developed and delivered an online group training program for Teach Me Skills school.
- Revamped, deployed, and currently maintain the Slurm GitLab CI course.
- Contributed as a speaker or expert in various Slurm courses.

#### Freelance (Spartan.com and smaller projects)

SEPTEMBER 2020 - OCTOBER 2021

Different projects in different domains (from several countries)

AWS GitLab CI Terraform Terragrunt Helm Helmfile Kubernetes Docker

# EPAM Systems (www.epam.com)

**Lead Systems Engineer** 

APRIL 2016 - AUGUST 2021

- Advanced from Junior Systems Engineer to Lead position, demonstrating leadership and technical expertise.
- Worked on diverse projects in various roles including Team Lead, Technical Lead, Maintenance Engineer, and Build Engineer.
- Designed and built midsize+ infrastructures on AWS, following best practices and emphasizing automation with Terraform.
- Developed and implemented CI/CD pipelines for multiple projects and products, streamlining development processes and improving efficiency.

#### Technologies:

AWS GCP Azure Terraform Terragrunt Ansible Packer Git Docker Kubernetes (Kops, EKS) Helm Bash Python Linux Windows Jenkins GitLab CI Travis GitHub Actions Grafana Elasticsearch Kibana Prometheus Loki

#### RUE Beltelecom (www.beltelecom.by) - Senior Engineer

MARCH 2011 - APRIL 2016

- Worked as the 1st and 2nd ISP Client support in the call center. Later was
  promoted to the network on-call engineer responsible for the backbone ISP
  network support and maintenance.
- Enterprise clients support (VPN and Ethernet\SHDSL Internet access).
- Initialised and developed multiple automation solution based on scripts for network equipment maintenance.

Huawei Cisco xDSL xPON ISP IPTV VoIP VPN Linux Zabbix